sdxcentral.com 2019-11-07

# Privacy Policy - SDxCentral.com

## SDxCentral Privacy Policy for SDxCentral.com

Last Update: May 8, 2018

SDxCentral, LLC (“SDxCentral”) provides this Privacy Policy to make you aware of our privacy practices and the choices you can make about how your personal information is collected through our websites and how it is used. To make this notice easy to access, it is available on the bottom of every SDxCentral.com web page.

Customers are SDxCentral’s most valuable asset. We recognize that building a long-term business relationship with you depends a great deal on trust. This trust begins with our commitment to respecting as well as protecting your privacy. Our privacy practices are self-certified as part of the U.S. Commerce Department’s Privacy Shield Program.

We’ve structured our website so that you can generally visit and browse the website without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information. Throughout this Privacy Policy, personal information refers to any information that is unique to an individual, such as name, address, e-mail address, phone number, etc.

SDxCentral’s Privacy Policy covers 9 main areas: Notice, Choice, Access & Accuracy, Onward Transfer, Security and Retention, and Oversight/Enforcement, Tailoring Email Communications and Web Experiences, How SDxCentral Uses Cookies and Additional Information.  These areas are described in detail below. Please keep in mind that our privacy practices may vary as required by local laws and policies. Comments or questions about our privacy practices can be sent to: [legal@sdxcentral.com](mailto:legal@sdxcentral.com)

### 1\. Notice

**What information we collect**

During the course of your relationship with us, we may collect personal information to enable you to register for webinars, view videos, listen to podcasts, download whitepapers, eBriefs, eBooks, slides and reports, make requests, setup client analytics account access for campaigns (if associated with a client account) and register for We may collect such personal information as your name, contact and billing information, transaction and credit card information.

We may collect this information, such as your name, contact and billing information, transaction and credit card information, when you enter into a contract with us to offer advertising and promotional services for you, as necessary to enter the contract.

We collect information that you enter to register for the website, download a whitepaper, eBrief, eBook, slides or report, view a webinar, listen to a podcast, take a survey, or actively engage with our other content, such as name, title, company, address, phone, email and password for our legitimate interests or based on your express consent.

To tailor our subsequent communications to you and improve our products and services, we may ask you to provide information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, experience with our products and contact preferences.

Personal information may be required to determine access eligibility for certain restricted parts of our website. Data collected on-line may be combined with information provided off-line.

We may track information that will be maintained, used and disclosed in aggregate form only and which will not contain your personally identifiable information.  For example, we may collect IP addresses and browser type and we may collect information on which articles, webinars, slides, videos, podcasts, whitepapers, eBriefs, eBooks, reports and other content are popular. We may analyze this data for trends and statistics in the aggregate, and we may use such aggregate information to administer the website, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.  We associate this aggregate data with a numerical identifier and not your name, so that it is pseudonymized.  Our email marketing provider, such as Mailchimp or Net-Results, may provide your IP, country, city and state to us when you open an email.

**How we use the information**

We use your personal information to enter into a contract with us, help you complete a transaction, to communicate back to you, remind you of scheduled webinars, send you newsletters to which you have subscribed, provide updates on service and benefits, and to personalize our websites and communications with you.

If we should collect credit card numbers from you, they will be used only for payment processing.

From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for our legitimate interest to perform market research or to provide you with marketing information we think would be of particular interest. We will give you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving such contact. If you would like to read more about how to opt-out, please follow the directions given below in the “Choice” section of this document. In addition, we will also follow local requirements where applicable.

We also use personal information for our legitimate interests to help us develop, deliver, and improve our services, content, and advertising.

From time to time, we may use your personal information to send important notices, such as communications about information available to purchase and changes to our terms, conditions, and policies.

We may also use personal information internally for our legitimate interests such as auditing, to detect fraud, data analysis, and research to improve SDxCentral’s services, and customer communications.

We do not process personal information in a way that is incompatible with the purposes for which it has been collected or subsequently authorized by you.

**Disclosure to Third Parties**

At times SDxCentral may make certain information available to service providers that work with SDxCentral that assist SDxCentral in providing its services. For example, to attend a webinar our webinar service provider requires your name and email address to provide the webinar to you.  You may elect not to share other information to attend the webinar.

With your consent, we share personal information with the sponsors and contributors to the SDxCentral webinars, slides, videos, podcasts,such as our advertising and promotion clients, for their own marketing purposes.

We may share your information with our affiliates within our corporate family/control group, which includes Wiretap Ventures LLC.  We will not otherwise transfer your personally identifiable information to any company or organization, but we may transfer your personally identifiable information to a successor entity upon a merger, consolidation or other corporate reorganization in which SDxCentral participates or to a purchaser or acquirer of all or substantially all of SDxCentral’s assets to which the web site relates.

**Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**

SDxCentral’s website is not directed to children under the age of 13. SDxCentral does not target its website to children under 13. SDxCentral does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that a child under the age of 13 provided us with personally identifiable information, we will delete that information.

### 2\. Choice

SDxCentral will not use or share your personal information in ways unrelated to the ones described above without first notifying you and offering a choice. We will also provide you the opportunity to let us know if you wish to opt-out at any time of certain or all contact from SDxCentral, and we will use reasonable efforts to honor such requests. This choice may be offered at the bottom of our on-line or off-line communications, including our newsletters, to you as well as on many of our web registration pages. If you have any difficulty exercising your choices, please send your request to: [legal@sdxcentral.com.](mailto:legal@sdxcentral.com)

### 3\. Onward Transfer

The personal information that you provide to us may be transferred within SDxCentral across state or country borders. This may be done to consolidate data storage or to simplify the management of customer information.

SDxCentral is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf, i.e. performing tasks on behalf of, and under the instruction of, SDxCentral.  In particular, SDxCentral remains responsible and liable under Privacy Shield Frameworks if third-party agents that it engages to process the personal data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the principles of the Privacy Shield Frameworks, unless SDxCentral proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.  If SDxCentral has knowledge that an agent is using or disclosing personal data in a manner contrary to this policy, SDxCentral will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop the use or disclosure.

### 4\. Access and Accuracy

SDxCentral uses reasonable efforts to keep your personal information accurate.

We will provide you with online access to your personal information so that you may review, update or correct your information at the SDxCentral site where it was submitted. If the law in your country allows us to impose a fee for giving you access, we will communicate this to you in response to your request.

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you access or enabling you to make corrections. To access your personal information, return to the web page where you originally entered it and follow the instructions on that web page. If you cannot access your information on the web page, please[ contact us using our support form](https://www.sdxcentral.com/inquiry/support/) (pick Privacy and Compliance Question).

In certain circumstances, you can also: revoke consent that you have provided; object to our use of your personal information for certain purposes; ask us to limit or restrict our use of your personal information; ask us to remove or delete personal information about you; or provide your personal information to a third party provider of services.

If you would like to exercise any of your rights in relation to your personal information, please[ contact us using our support form](https://www.sdxcentral.com/inquiry/support/) (pick Privacy and Compliance Question).

### 5\. Security and Retention

To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of personal information, we have put in place reasonably appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures that are designed to safeguard and secure it, such as encryption, firewalls, password restrictions and other internal restrictions.  All supplied credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our payment gateway providers database.

We only keep your personal information for as long as we need to, to be able to use it for the reasons given in this privacy policy, and for as long as we are required to keep it by law.

### 6\. Oversight/Enforcement

SDxCentral privacy practices are self-certified as part of the U.S. Commerce Department’s Privacy Shield Program. For more information and to view our certification, please go to the Privacy Shield Program website at [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

### 7\. Tailoring E-Mail Communications and Web Experiences

On occasion SDxCentral may employ technologies that enable us to review which recipients have opened our e-mail communications and which links they have accessed in the message. This helps us to tailor our communications in our attempts to send you the most relevant information, as local laws and your preferences and permissions allow. As a registered user, we may also monitor your web browsing session while you are logged-in to SDxCentral.com. In this way we will try to improve our website through personalization to better meet your needs.   We currently do not follow do not track signals from your browser.

### 8\. Cookies

A cookie is a piece of information either stored temporarily in your browser’s memory space (session cookie) or placed on your computer’s hard drive (stored or persistent cookie). Cookies allow a web application to respond to you as an individual, but without the need to identify you explicitly. Session cookies are destroyed when you terminate your browsing session by shutting down your browser. Stored cookies often have a predetermined expiration date after which they disappear from your hard drive. Cookies can be removed explicitly through functionality built into most web browsers. You may also set your web browser (e.g. Microsoft Internet Explorer or Firefox) to notify you of cookie placement requests, ask for permission to accept them, or decline cookies completely.  
**  
Usage of Cookies and Other related Technologies**

SDxCentral may use cookies and other technologies to help us analyze web traffic or to improve your web navigation experience. To facilitate the analysis, an ID is assigned to help us uniquely identify you each time you return to our website. One of the major concerns about stored cookies is the fear that they contain personal information and information identifying you that could be accessed by other websites. SDxCentral only stores a randomly chosen unique ID number and a context, both of which are meaningless to others, but help us uniquely identify you. Cookies and other technologies may also be used to control the number of times you see a given ad or other material, deliver ads and other material that relate to your interests, measure the effectiveness of ad campaigns and otherwise assist us in making your use of the SDxCentral material more relevant and useful to you.

By gathering and remembering information about your preferences, the website can:

  * Tailor its operation to your needs, likes and dislikes
  * Provide an automated log-in process as a convenience for previously registered customers. This insures that you will be accurately identified and linked with your registration data.
  * place cookies on your computer to ensure you are not surveyed multiple times during your visit(s) to an SDxCentral website. This cookie has a limited life span and will not personally identify you.

Cookies help us provide a better web experience by letting us monitor what’s working and what isn’t through site traffic analysis. SDxCentral wants to be sure you understand that accepting a cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any personal information about you, other than the data you chose to share with us. While acknowledging the concerns that some visitors have about cookie usage, we believe that the benefit our website visitors gain from the use of cookies is worthwhile.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on your visit to our sites and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

### 9\. Additional Information

**Links to Third-Party** **Websites**

Links to third-party websites are provided solely as a convenience to you. If you use these links, you will leave the SDxCentral site. SDxCentral has not reviewed all of these third-party websites; does not control and is not responsible for any of these sites, their content or their privacy policies. Thus, we do not endorse or make any representations about them, or any information, software or other products or materials found there, or any results that may be obtained from using them. If you decide to access any of the third-party sites linked to this website, you do so entirely at your own risk.

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**

SDxCentral may update its Privacy Policy from time to time. When we change the policy in a material way, a notice will be posted on our website along with the updated Privacy Policy and/or through another reasonable means of communication. Users are bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when he or she uses the website after such notice has been provided.

**European Union / Swiss Users and Privacy Shield**

Information you provide may be transferred or accessed by entities around the world as described in this Privacy Policy.  SDxCentral participates in and has certified its compliance with both the EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively.  SDxCentral is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Frameworks, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. Learn more about the [U.S. Department of Commerce Privacy Shield Program.](https://www.privacyshield.gov/)  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Frameworks, the Privacy Shield Frameworks shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

SDxCentral complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions set forth above in the section entitled “Onward Transfer”.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, SDxCentral is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, SDxCentral may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including as necessary to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

**Dispute Resolution under Privacy Shield**

In compliance with the Privacy Shield, SDxCentral is committed to resolve complaints about privacy and the collection or use of personal information. If you have a complaint or question, please contact us at [legal@sdxcentral.com.](mailto:legal@sdxcentral.com) SDxCentral will investigate and attempt to resolve disputes regarding use and disclosure of your personal information within 45 days in accordance with the principles contained in our privacy policy.

SDxCentral has enrolled with [JAMS](https://www.jamsadr.com/), an alternative dispute resolution provider located in the US with offices in Massachusetts (One Beacon Street, Suite 2210, Boston, MA 02108) to assist with the complaint resolution process. JAMS is SDxCentral’s only means of resolving disputes under Privacy Shield; all complaints submitted to JAMS shall be resolved via arbitration. Should you feel that SDxCentral has not resolved to your satisfaction any inquiry regarding use of personal information under Privacy Shield, you can submit a complaint to JAMS through this page: <https://www.jamsadr.com/file-an-eu-us-privacy-shield-or-safe-harbor-claim>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the [Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), a Member may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

### Contact Information

If you have any questions or concerns about SDxCentral’s privacy policy please e-mail us  [legal@sdxcentral.com](mailto:legal@sdxcentral.com)
